Finding Aid for Eugene B. Power papers, 1937-1993
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Organizational activities and personal interests
  - Topical files, mainly, 1975-1977
    - World Health Foundation (Box 73)
    - Xerox Corporation (Box 73)
  - Topical files, mainly, 1978-1981
    - American Trust for the British Library (Box 74)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 74)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 75)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 76)
    - Ann Arbor Symphony (Box 76)
    - Anniversary (50th) (Box 76)
    - Barton Hills (Box 76)
    - Battle Abbey School (Box 76)
    - Biographical data (Box 76)
    - Bliss Hunting Preserve (Box 76)
    - Bonavia Bedding (Box 76)
    - Borsook, Eve (Box 76)
    - Brown University Library (Box 76)
    - Business Committee for the Arts (Box 76)
    - China (Box 76)
    - Christmas (Box 76)
    - Committees and Boards (Box 76)
    - Common Cause (Box 76)
    - Condominium Purchase (Box 76)
    - Connable Office (Box 76)
    - Contributions (Box 76)
    - Cook, Clifford (Box 77)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 77)
    - Daedalus Enterprises (Box 77)
    - Daedalus Enterprises (Box 78)
    - Detroit Institute of Art (Box 78)
    - Dinner Group (Box 78)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 78)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 79)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 80)
    - Education (Box 80)
    - Enterprises (include E.F. Hutton) (Box 80)
    - Environmental Research Institute of Michigan (ERIM) (Box 80)
    - Environmental Research Institute of Michigan (ERIM) (Box 81)
    - Genealogy (Box 82)
    - Goddard, Mrs. Wendell (Box 82)
    - Greenebaum, Edgar (Box 82)
    - Hastings, Battle of (Box 82)
    - Infodata (Box 82)
    - Interlochen Arts Academy (Box 82)
    - International Husky (Box 82)
    - International Micrographic Congress (Box 82)
    - Itineraries (Box 82)
    - Knights of the British Empire (Box 82)
    - KVOR (Colorado Springs) (Box 82)
    - Lathem, Edward C. (Box 82)
    - Letters of Condolences (Box 82)
    - Magdalene College (Box 82)
    - Marion Islands (Box 82)
    - Michigan Capital and Service (Box 82)
    - Michigan Council for the Arts (Box 82)
    - Michigan Historical Collections (Box 82)
    - Michigan Space Center (Box 82)
    - Microfilming (Box 82)
    - Naset, Martha (Box 82)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 82)
    - National Micrographics Association (Box 83)
    - Nature Conservancy (Box 83)
    - Ormandy, Eugene (Box 83)
    - Park Place Motor Inn (Box 83)
    - Park Place Motor Inn (Box 84)
    - Political (Box 84)
    - Power (Frank) family members (Box 85)
    - Power family members (Box 85)
    - Power Center for the Performing Arts (Box 85)
    - Power Foundation (Box 85)
    - Power Foundation (Box 86)
    - Regent Emeritus (Box 86)
    - Regent Emeritus (Box 87)
    - St. Joseph's Mercy Hospital (Box 87)
    - Shaws, Mrs. Jackson (Box 88)
    - Socha, Norma & Erla (Box 88)
    - Suburban Communications (Box 88)
    - Travel/Tours (Box 88)
    - Twin Lakes Club (Box 88)
    - United Negro College Fund (Box 88)
    - United States-China Relations (Box 88)
    - University Microfilms (Box 88)
    - Wine (Box 88)
    - World Wildlife Fund (Box 88)
    - Xerox Corporation (Box 88)
  - Topical files, mainly, 1981-1983
    - American Philosophical Society (Box 89)
    - American Trust for the British Library (Box 89)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 89)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 90)
    - Ann Arbor Symphony (Box 91)
    - Arbor-A Inc. (Box 91)
    - Ars Musica (Box 91)
    - Awards and honors (Box 91)
    - Barton Hills (Box 91)
    - Biographical data (Box 91)
    - Bliss Hunting Preserve (Box 91)
    - Borsook, Eve (Box 91)
    - Christmas (Box 91)
    - Connable Office (Box 91)
    - Contributions (Box 91)
    - Cook, Clifford (deceased) (Box 91)
    - Coolidge, Jack (Box 91)
    - Correspondence (Box 91)
    - Daedalus Enterprises (Box 92)
    - Detroit Institute of Art (Box 92)
    - Detroit Symphony Orchestra (Box 92)
    - Dinner Group (Box 92)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 92)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 93)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 94)
    - Enterprises (include E.F. Hutton) (Box 95)
    - Environmental Research Institute of Michigan (ERIM) (Box 95)
    - Greenhills School (Box 95)
    - Hastings, Battle of (Box 95)
    - International Information Congress (Box 95)
    - International Micrographic Congress (Box 95)
    - Knights of the British Empire (Box 95)
    - KVOR (Colorado Springs) (Box 96)
    - Letters of Recommendation (Box 96)
    - Magdalene College (Box 96)
    - Marion Islands (Box 96)
    - Microfilming (Box 96)
    - Naset, Martha (Box 96)
    - Nature Conservancy (Box 96)
    - Planned Parenthood (Box 96)
    - Plymouth Office Building (Box 96)
    - Political (Box 96)
    - Power, Thomas (Box 96)
    - Power Foundation (Box 97)
    - Power Foundation (Box 98)
    - Promissory Notes (Box 99)
    - Regent Emeritus (Box 99)
    - Roberson, Mary Lou Morrison (Box 99)
    - Runge, Margaret (Box 99)
    - Safari (Box 99)
    - St. Joseph's Mercy Hospital (Box 99)
    - Sharemet, John (Box 99)
    - Shaw, Verena (Box 99)
    - Socha, Norma & Erla (Box 99)
    - Twin Lakes Club (Box 99)
    - United Negro College Fund (Box 99)
    - University Microfilms (Box 99)
  - Topical files, mainly, 1983-1985
    - American Philosophical Society (Box 100)
    - Ann Arbor Nuclear, Inc. (Box 100)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 100)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 101)
    - Ars Musica (Box 101)
    - Association for Information & Image Management (Box 101)
    - Catherine McAuley Health Center (Box 101)
    - Cavallini, Sauro (Box 101)
    - Committees and Boards (Box 101)
    - Connable Office (Box 101)
    - Contributions (Box 101)
    - Coolidge, John (Box 101)
    - Coolidge, Susan (Box 101)
    - Correspondence (Box 101)
    - Crosby, Albert (Box 102)
    - Daedalus Enterprises (Box 102)
    - Detroit Institute of Art (Box 102)
    - Detroit Symphony Orchestra (Box 102)
    - Dinner Group (Box 102)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 102)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 103)
    - Education (Box 103)
    - Enterprises (include E.F. Hutton) (Box 103)
    - Environmental Research Institute of Michigan (ERIM) (Box 103)
    - Goddard, Mrs. Wendell (Box 104)
    - Health insurance (Box 104)
    - Infodata (Box 104)
    - Judge, Paul C. (Box 104)
    - Maini, Marie-Liese (Box 104)
    - Michigan Capital and Service (Box 104)
    - Ormandy, Eugene (Box 104)
    - Park Place Motor Inn (Box 104)
    - Parkinson's Disease information (Box 104)
    - Planned Parenthood (Box 104)
    - Plymouth Office Building (Box 104)
    - Political (Box 104)
    - Population Crisis Committee (Box 104)
    - Power Foundation (Box 104)
    - Power Foundation (Box 105)
    - Regent Emeritus (Box 105)
    - Runge, Margaret (Box 105)
    - Safari (Box 105)
    - Shaw, Verena (Box 105)
    - Socha, Norma (Box 105)
    - Suburban Communications (Box 105)
    - Travel/Tours (Box 105)
    - Trepte, Kai (Box 105)
    - Twin Lakes Club (Box 105)
    - United Negro College Fund (Box 105)
    - University Microfilms (Box 105)
    - Welch, Dorothy (Box 105)
    - Works of Art (Box 105)
    - World Wildlife Fund (Box 105)
  - Topical files, mainly, 1985-1987
    - American Philosophical Society (Box 106)
    - Ann Arbor Area, 2000 (Box 106)
    - Ann Arbor Nuclear, Inc. (Box 106)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 106)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 107)
    - Ann Arbor Symphony (Box 107)
    - Arktronics (Box 107)
    - Arsenic Company (Box 107)
    - Barton Hills (Box 107)
    - Biographical data (Box 107)
    - Catherine McAuley Health Center (Box 107)
    - Cavallini, Sauro (Box 107)
    - Chace, Daniel (Box 107)
    - Christmas (Box 107)
    - Committees and Boards (Box 107)
    - Contributions (Box 107)
    - Contributions (Box 108)
    - Cook, Ann (Box 108)
    - Correspondence (Box 108)
    - Detroit Symphony Orchestra (Box 108)
    - Dinner Group (Box 108)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 109)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 110)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 111)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 112)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 113)
    - Environmental Research Institute of Michigan (ERIM) (Box 113)
    - Income tax (Box 114)
    - Individualized Home Nursing Care (Box 114)
    - Insurance (Mundus and Mundus) (Box 114)
    - International Information Management Congress (Box 114)
    - Marion Islands (Box 114)
    - Michigan Theatre (Box 114)
    - Mime Center (Box 115)
    - Nachazel, Kathryn (Box 115)
    - Plymouth Office Building (Box 115)
    - Political (Box 116)
    - Population Crisis Committee (Box 116)
    - Power, Philip (Box 116)
    - Power, Sadye (Box 116)
    - Power, Sarah (include letters of condolence received upon her death), 1987 (Box 116)
    - Power Foundation (Box 116)
    - Power Foundation (Box 117)
    - Power Foundation (Box 118)
    - Regent Emeritus (Box 118)
    - Twin Lakes Club (Box 118)
    - United Negro College Fund (Box 118)
    - Weaver, Keith (Box 118)
    - Wright, Beverly (Box 118)
    - Xerox Corporation (Box 118)
  - Topical files, mainly, 1988-1989
    - American Philosophical Society, 1988-1989 (Box 119)
    - Ann Arbor, 1987-1989 (Box 119)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival, 1987-1990
      - Administrative, 1987-1989; 9 folders (Box 119)
      - Board of Trustees, 1987-1989; 4 folders (Box 119)
      - Contributions, 1987-1989; 4 folders (Box 119)
      - Fundraising, 1987-1990; 12 folders (Box 119)
    - Barton Hills (Medical Care), 1988-1989 (Box 119)
    - Biographies, 1975-1989
      - Anderson, Robert, 1988-1989; 4 folders (Box 120)
      - Mayor, Archie, 1987-1988 (Box 120)
      - Hall, Donald, 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 120)
    - Christmas, 1988-1989 (Box 120)
    - Citizens for Public Art, 1988 (Box 120)
    - Condolence letters, 1984-1988 (Box 120)
    - Contributions, 1986-1988 (Box 120)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1989; 4 folders (Box 120)
    - Dinner Group, 1987-1989 (Box 120)
    - Domino's Pizza, 1987-1989
      - General, 2 folders (Box 120)
      - Audits, 2 folders (Box 120)
      - Directors' Fees, 2 folders (Box 120)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, 5 folders (Box 120)
      - Board of Directors Meetings, 19 folders (Box 121)
      - Detroit Tigers (Box 121)
      - Distribution (Box 121)
      - Executive Team, 2 folders (Box 121)
      - International, 5 folders (Box 122)
      - Domino's Farms, 2 folders (Box 122)
      - Financial, 9 folders (Box 122)
      - Domino's Foundation, 2 folders (Box 122)
      - Thomas S. Monaghan, 5 folders (Box 122)
      - Thomas S. Monaghan, 5 folders (Box 123)
      - Operating Results/Statistics, 3 folders (Box 123)
    - E.F. Hutton (Box 123)
    - Magdalene College Honorary Fellow, 1984-1988 (Box 124)
    - Maini, Mary-Liese, 1987-1988 (Box 124)
    - Marceau Mime Center, 1987-1989 (Box 124)
    - Measuretek (Box 124)
    - Michigan Theater, 1988-1989 (Box 124)
    - Ormandy, Eugene, 1984-1985 (Box 124)
    - Park Place (Box 124)
    - Political, 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 124)
    - Power Is, 1988 (Box 124)
    - Power, Philip, 1985-1989 (Box 124)
    - Power Foundation, 1987-1990
      - Administration and Finance, 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Annual Reports, 3 folders (Box 124)
      - General, 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Early Childhood Development: Sadye Power Fund, 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Massialas, Margaret, 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Nissman, Barbara, 4 folders (Box 124)
      - Randolph/Adams Fund (Box 125)
      - Scholarship Policy (Box 125)
      - Taxes (Box 125)
      - Scholarships: U-M and Cambridge, 6 folders (Box 125)
      - Scholarships: U-M and Cambridge, 18 folders (Box 125)
    - Regent Emeritus, 1987-1989
      - General, 2 folders (Box 125)
      - Gifts to UM, 2 folders (Box 125)
      - Medical School/Hospital, 2 folders (Box 125)
      - Museum of Art (Box 125)
      - Musical Society (Box 125)
      - Music School (Box 125)
      - Power Center (Box 125)
      - Rackham Graduate School (Box 125)
      - Sarah Goodard Power Award (Box 125)
      - University Library (Box 125)
    - Rotary Club of Ann Arbor, 1987-1989 (Box 125)
    - Suburban Communications (Box 125)
    - Trepte, 1985-1988 (Box 125)
    - Traverse City, 1986-1988 (Box 125)
    - Travel/Tours, 1985-1989 (Box 125)
    - United Negro College Fund, 1986-1989 (Box 126)
    - University Microfilms, 8 folders (Box 126)
    - White, Joel, 1987-1988 (Box 126)
    - Works of Art, 1986-1989; 4 folders (Box 126)
  - Topical files, mainly, 1989-1991
    - American Philosophical Society (Box 126)
    - American Trust for the British Library (Box 126)
    - Ann Arbor Art Association (Box 126)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 126)
    - Awards and honors (Box 126)
    - Bank accounts (Box 126)
    - Barrigar, Neil (Box 126)
    - Barton Hills (Box 126)
    - Biographical data (Box 126)
    - Catherine McAuley Health Center (Box 126)
    - Christmas (Box 126)
    - Citizens for Public Art (Box 126)
    - Committees and Boards (Box 126)
    - Computers (Box 126)
    - Connable Office (Box 126)
    - Contributions (Box 127)
    - Correspondence (Box 127)
    - Dinner Group (Box 127)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 127)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 128)
    - E.F. Hutton (Box 128)
    - Elliot Martin Co. (Box 128)
    - Enterprises & investments (Box 128)
    - Environmental Research Institute of Michigan (ERIM) (Box 128)
    - Esch, Donald J. (Box 129)
    - Goddard, Mrs. Wendell (Box 129)
    - Grayangel Weimaraners (Box 129)
    - Greenhills School (Box 129)
    - Harkness Fellowship (Box 129)
    - Health insurance (Box 129)
    - Letters of Recommendation (Box 129)
    - Letters of Condolence (Box 129)
    - Linowitz, Sol (Box 129)
    - March of America (Box 129)
    - Measurek, Inc. (Box 129)
    - Medical information (Box 129)
    - Mime Center (Box 129)
    - Park Place Motor Inn (Box 129)
    - Planned Parenthood (Box 129)
    - Plymouth Office Building (Box 129)
    - Population Crisis Committee (Box 129)
    - Power Foundation (Box 130)
    - Regent Emeritus (Box 130)
    - Safari (Box 130)
    - St. John's University (Box 130)
    - Shaw-Baum, Verena (Box 130)
    - Travel/Tours (Box 130)
    - Trepte, Kai (Box 130)
    - University Microfilms (Box 130)
    - Washtenaw Community College (Box 130)
    - Wine (Box 130)
    - Xerox Corporation (Box 130)
  - Topical files, mainly, 1990-1993
    - American Philosophical Society (Box 131)
    - American Trust for the British Library (Box 131)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 131)
    - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 132)
    - Association for Information & Image Management (Box 132)
    - Awards and honors (Box 132)
    - Borsook, Eve (Box 132)
    - Correspondence (Box 133)
    - Dinner Group (Box 133)
    - Dinner Group (Box 134)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 134)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 135)
    - Eskimo Art, Inc. (Box 135)
    - Fraternities (Box 136)
    - Harkness Fellowship (Box 136)
    - Interlochen Arts Academy (Box 136)
    - International Information Management Congress (Box 136)
    - Letters of Condolence (Box 136)
    - Ormandy, Mrs. Eugene (Box 136)
    - Planned Parenthood (Box 136)
    - Political (Box 136)
    - Power, Frank (Box 136)
    - Power, Robert (Box 136)
    - Power, Sadye (Box 136)
      (include papers re publication of book about her)
    - Power, Thomas G. (Box 136)
    - Power Foundation (Box 137)
    - Power Foundation (Box 138)
    - Power Foundation (Box 139)
    - Power Foundation (Box 140)
    - Power Foundation (Box 141)
    - Power Foundation (Box 142)
    - Power Foundation (Box 143)
    - Power Foundation (Box 144)
    - Regent Emeritus (Box 144)
    - Roger M. Jones Fellowship (Box 144)
    - Safari (Box 144)
    - St. John's University (Box 144)
    - United Negro College Fund (Box 144)
    - University Microfilms (Box 144)
    - White, Joel (Box 144)
- Photographs
  - Career and family photos (Box 144)
- Sound Recordings, reel-to-reel audiotapes
  - Conversations with EBP used in preparation of possible biography (Box 144)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Box 144)
- Microfilmed papers
  (These microfilm reels consist of papers, most of which may be found in the first 28 boxes of the collection.)
  - Chronological files
    - 1937-1938 (Box 145, Reel 1)
    - 1939-1948 (Box 145, Reel 2)
    - 1949-April 1958 (Box 145, Reel 3)
    - May 1958-1961 (Box 145, Reel 4)
    - 1962-1964 (Box 145, Reel 5)
    - 1965-1970 (Box 145, Reel 6)
  - Projected Books Project, 1944-1959
    - 1944-1946 (Box 145, Reel 6)
    - 1957-1959 (Box 145, Reel 7)
  - Trip to the Orient, 1955 (Box 145, Reel 7)
  - Trip to Russia, July 1960 (Box 145, Reel 8)
  - Campaign Speeches, 1955 (Box 145, Reel 8)
  - State Democratic Convention Campaign (Box 145, Reel 9)
  - Board of Regents, UM, 1959 (Box 145, Reel 9)
  - Board of Regents, UM, 1960 (Box 145, Reel 10)
  - Power Draft for Democratic Education, 1961 (Box 145, Reel 10)
  - Democratic Candidates, 1959 (Box 145, Reel 11)
  - Power's Article on Education (Box 145, Reel 11)
  - Miscellaneous EBP speeches, correspondence, and UMI reports, 8 reels (Box 145, Reel 12-19)
  - Negative microfilm copies of positive copies located in box 145 (Box 146)
    [staff use only]